George Salter Papers, 1920-1980
Mortimer Rare Book Room, William Allan Neilson Library, Smith College
George Salter Papers
1920-1980
Salter, George, 1897-1967
4
5 boxes (2901 items) (2 linear ft.)
Mortimer Rare Book Room Smith College Northampton, MA
German-born book designer, illustrator, calligrapher, teacher, and scenic designer who moved to the United States in the mid-1930's. Consists of books designed by George Salter and books reflecting his professional interests (704 items), together with proofs, papers, and ephemera relating to his design projects (2,901 pieces).
Biographical Note
George Salter (1897-1967), book designer and calligrapher was born in Bremen, Germany, 5 October 1897, of Protestant Jewish origin. His father Norbert Salter, born in Austria, was a conservator of music, a cellist and an impresario. His mother, Stefanie Klein, born in Hungary, was an opera singer.
George Salter graduated from the Abitur, Helmholtz Gymnasium, in 1916, and did his military service for the German Army in 1917-1918. The following year he studied privately with Ewald Dülberg, and from 1919 to 1924, he studied graphic arts at the School of Arts and Crafts in Berlin with Harold Bengen. In 1921-1922, Salter worked with theater workshops of the Prussian State Theater with Willy Jaeckel and Klaus Richter. From 1922 to 1924 he worked first as an assistant then as a stage designer for various German theaters and opera houses, including Grosse Volksoper, Berlin (1922-1924), Städtliches Opern und Theaterhaus Barmen Elberfeld, Rhineland (1924-1926), and Städtliches Opernhaus Berlin-Charlottenburg.
In 1927 Salter turned from stage design to typography and lettering, and for six years he worked as a book designer and illustrator for more than twenty German publishing companies, including S. Fisher and Kiepenheuer.
From 1931 to 1933, Salter worked as department head of applied graphics and commercial art at Höhere Graphishe Fachschule (Berlin Graphic Arts Academy) in Berlin until he was dismissed in March 1933. Salter moved to Baden Baden after being prohibited from work, and emigrated to the U.S. in 1934. In 1935 Salter was expelled from the Reichskulturkammer (R.K.K.).
A year before Salter emigrated, in November 1933, fifty of Salter's book jackets were displayed in a show at Columbia University, arranged by Hellmuth Lehmann-Haupt. George Salter's younger brother Stefan, also a well known book designer, had already been in America for seven years before George arrived. Designer Ernst Reichl had gone to school with Stefan, knew of George's work and recommended him to Bertram Wolff, of H. Wollff Book Manufacturing Co. Mr. Wollff arranged for Salter's passage to the U.S. and employed him as a designer.
In America, Salter settled in New York as a freelance book jacket designer and illustrator. His first commission was with H. Wolff Books, New York. In 1935-1936 he taught book design and lettering at the School for Library Service of Columbia University on the recommendation of Dr. Lehmann-Haupt. In 1937-1967, he was adjunct professor at Cooper Union Art School, New York, and he also taught at New York University. In 1939-1957, Salter held the position of artistic director of Mercury Publications, New York. In 1960 Salter was the designer and artistic adviser for Atlas Magazine in New York.
Salter created jackets and book designs for many leading publishing houses including Simon & Schuster, Knopf, Basic Books, Bobbs-Merrill, Random House, Little Brown, and Viking, among others. He designed trade marks for the 20th Century Fund, Lincoln Center, and Atlas among others, and lettered a popular UNICEF Christmas card.
George Salter influenced other graphic designers in the U.S. during his 30 years of teaching, and many of his students became very successful. His work aimed at making the book jacket an integral part of the design of the book and not only a decorative element. In an interview with Publishers Weekly he said that his job as an artist was "to serve the book." His jacket art was allusive and not only literal. He explained: "If a manuscript hits me, then I let it speak in the language I can express."
Salter's book jackets won high praise for their beauty of execution and representation of the spirit and content of the books. He often designed the complete book-text, cover design, jacket and illustrations. In the book printing field, it is said that Salter influenced the trend toward offset printing. Much of his artwork was done with airbrush technique, and he favored offset lithography for faithful reproduction of his particular style.
Salter was also greatly respected for his fine calligraphy. Together with Paul Standard, he is given credit for stimulating the rebirth of calligraphy in the U.S.
Salter's work was exhibited in both individual and group exhibitions like the Artists' Guild of New York, Guild of German Book Artist (Munich, 1956), and "Fifty Books of the Year" shows of the American Institute of Graphic Arts. A coast-to-coast exhibition of his work was circulated in 1961-1962, starting at Gallery 303, New York.
Salter was the author of Book Jacket in the U.S.A. He belonged to the American Institute of Graphic Arts, the Book Jacket Design Guild, the Society for Italio Handwriting of London, and the Grolier Club.
In 1942 George Salter married Agnes O'Shea, who was born in Northampton, Massachusetts in 1901. Salter retired from his teaching at Cooper Union Art School in May 1967. Three weeks after his 70th birthday he died on October 31, 1967 at Beth Israel Hospital in New York. He was survived by his wife Agnes O'Shea Salter, their daughter Janet Salter Rosenberg, and his brother Stefan Salter.
[Source: Hansen, Thomas S. Classic Book Jackets: The Design Legacy of George Salter (New York: Princeton Architectural Press, 2005)]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The collection of George Salter Papers was donated to Smith College on 17 October 1989 by his daughter Jane Salter Rosenberg, Class of 1954, and Herbert Rosenberg, in honor of Agnes O'Shea Salter, Class of 1927, and George Salter.
After the death of George Salter (calligrapher, illustrator and book designer) on 31 October 1967, a large portion of Salter's material was given to the Newberry Library. Preceding the death of Salter's wife Agnes O'Shea Salter, their daughter Janet Salter Rosenberg and husband Herbert Rosenberg donated the present collection.
The collection received by the Mortimer Rare Book Room at Smith College consists of books designed by George Salter and books reflecting his professional interests (704 items), together with proofs, papers, and ephemera relating to his design projects (2,901 pieces). Additional volumes from Salter's reference library (401 items) were presented to the Hillyer Art Library at Smith College.
The books with George Salter's book jackets are cataloged in the Mortimer Rare Book Room's stacks. The proofs, papers, and ephemera are arranged in five series, including Artwork by George Salter, Personal Papers, Biographical Papers, Appendix, and Oversize.
All of the items in the collection are in good condition.
(Please note: the appendix contains additional material about the George Salter Collection)
Organization of the Collection
This collection is organized into five series:
I. Artwork by George Salter, 1934-1967
II. Personal Papers, 1920-1966
III. Biographical Papers, 1940-1980
IV. Appendix
V. Oversize, 1936-1964
Additions to the Collection, 2004
Additions to the Collection, 2010
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
History of the Collection
The collection of George Salter Papers was donated to Smith College on 17 October 1989 by his daughter Jane Salter Rosenberg, Class of 1954, and Herbert Rosenberg, in honor of Agnes O'Shea Salter, Class of 1927, and George Salter.
After the death of George Salter (calligrapher, illustrator and book designer) on 31 October 1967, a large portion of Salter's material was given to the Newberry Library. Preceding the death of Salter's wife Agnes O'Shea Salter, their daughter Janet Salter Rosenberg and husband Herbert Rosenberg donated the present collection.
Search Terms
Salter, George, 1897-1967.; Dulberg, Ewald, 1888-1933.; Book designers--Germany.; Book designers--United States.; Book jackets--Germany--Design.; Book jackets--United States--Design.; Calligraphers--United States.
APPENDIX: Book Covers Designed by Salter in Series I
Abandoned, The Gallico, Paul Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:55
Absalom, Absalom! Faulkner, William Random House 1936 2:80
Adventures in Time and Space Healy, Raymond and McComas, J. Francis (eds.) Random House 1946 3:81
Affair, The Koningsberger, Hans Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:61
Alfred Nobel Paulia, Herta E. L.B. Fisher n.d. 1:24
All Aboard For Ararat Wells, H.G. Alliance n.d. 1:2
All Honorable Men Karp, David Knopf, Alfred A. 1956 2:54
American Harvest Bishop, John Peale and Tate, Allen (eds.) L.B. Fisher n.d. 1:24
Ancient Sun Kingdoms of the Americas, The von Hagen, Victor W. World Publ. Co. 1960 3:105
Andry Dust Gubsky, Nikolai Oxford University Press 1937 2:74
Anthology of Famous American Stories, An Burrell, Angus and Cerf, Bennett (eds.) Random House 1953 3:81
Anthology of Famous British Stories, An Cerf, Bennett and Moriarty, Henry (eds.) Random House 1953? 3:81
Apple in the Attic Jordan, Mildred Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Aran Islands, The Synge, John M. Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:59
Arch of Triumph Remarque, Erich Maria Appleton-Century n.d. 1:5
Art of Happiness, The Powys, John Cowper Simon and Schuster Inc. 1935 3:93
Atlas Magazine Atlas Mar-61 1:7
Atlas Magazine Atlas Aug-61 1:7
Atlas Magazine Atlas May-62 1:7
Atlas Magazine Atlas Jun-62 1:7
Atlas Magazine Atlas Jul-62 1:7
Atlas Magazine Atlas Aug-62 1:7
Atlas Magazine Atlas Oct-62 1:7
Atlas Shrugged Rand, Ayn Random House 1957 3:83
Atoms, Men and Stars Rusk, Rogers D. Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Auf den Trummern Dos Passos, John S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:27
B.F.'s Daughter Marquand, John P. Little Brown and Co. 1946 2:65
Back of Town Wolff, Maritta Random House 1951 3:81
Balcony, The Bell, Adrian Simon and Schuster Inc. 1935 3:94
Balladen Villon Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:44
Bang the Drum Slowly Harris, Mark Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:53
Barbara oder die Frommigkeit Werfel, Franz Paul Szolsnay Verlag n.d. 3:96
Barotique Mystery, The Coxe, George Harmon Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:52
Bedside Book of Famous American Stories Burrell, Angus and Cerf, Bennett (eds.) Random House 1946 3:81
Bedside Book of Famous French Stories Becker, Belle and Linscott, Robert (eds.) Random House 1945 3:81
Bell for Adano, A Hersey, John Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Berlin Diary Shirer, William L Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:50
Best of Art Young, The Vanguard 1936 3:100
Bestie erwacht, Die O'Flaherty, Liam S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:25
Beware of Pity Zweig, Stefan Viking Press Inc. 1939 3:102
Beyond Tears Litten, Irmgard Alliance n.d. 1:2
Beyond This Place Cronin, A.J. Little Brown and Co. 1953 2:67
Big Nickelodeon, The Wolff, Maritta Random House 1956 3:82
Big Sky, The Guthrie, A.B. Time Inc. 1964 3:98
Black Symbol, The Johnson, Annabel and Edgar Harper 1958 1:35
Blessed are the Meek Kossak, Zofia Roy Publishers 1943 3:90
Bond Between Us Loomis, Frederic Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:52
Book of the Symphony, A Haggin, B.H. Methuen 1937 2:72
Book-of-the-Month Club News The Book-of-the-Month Club Apr-44 1:11
Book-of-the-Month Club News The Book-of-the-Month Club Jun-44 1:11
Book-of-the-Month Club News The Book-of-the-Month Club Sep-44 1:11
Book-of-the-Month Club News The Book-of-the-Month Club Apr-46 1:11
Borzoi Books: Autumn 1936 Knopf, Alfred A. 1936 2:53
Borzoi Books: Autumn 1937 Knopf, Alfred A. 1937 1:52
Borzoi Books: Autumn 1937 Knopf, Alfred A. 1937 2:53
Borzoi Poe, The Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:50
Boys and Their Mother, The Jennison, Keith W. Viking Press Inc. 1955 3:102
Bread and Wine Silone, Ignazio Harper 1937 1:35
Breaking Into Print Simon and Schuster Inc. 1937 3:94
Bridge of the Brocade Sash, The Sitwell, Sacheverell World Publ. Co. 1959 3:105
Bridge, The Frankau, Pamela Harper 1957 1:35
Bright Promise, The Sherman, Richard Little Brown and Co. 1947 2:66
Brothers Ashkenazi, The Singer, J.J. Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Brucknerstrasse Herisko, Ilona Messner 1964 2:71
Bucher Verzeich
Bucher Verzeich nis 1928 Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:46
Bula Matari: das Leben Stanleys Wasserman, Jakob S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:27
Buried Land, A Jones, Madison Viking Press Inc. 1962 3:102
Buschfrieg Heuser, Kurt S. Fisher Bucherei n.d. 1:26
Byzantine Empress Diehl, Charles Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:58
Camberwell Beauty, The Golding, Louis Farrar and Rhinehart n.d. 1:22
Camus Notebooks 1935-1942 Thody, Philip Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:61
Camus Notebooks 1942-1951 O'Brien, Justin Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:61
Caribbean: Sea of the New World Arciniegas, German Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:53
Carrington Straight, Michael Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:59
Castle Garac Monsarrat, Nicholas Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:54
Castle, The Kafka, Franz Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:54
Celluloid Asylum, The Alexander, Sidney Bobbs-Merrill n.d. 1:10
Chapin Sisters, The Rowe, Fynette A.A. Wyn 1945 3:106
Chico Goes to the Wars Ormsbee, David Dutton n.d. 1:20
Child of Our Time del Castillo, Michel Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:56
China Court Godden, Rumer Viking Press Inc. n.d. 3:102
China Geheim Kisch, Egon Erwin Erich Reiss Verlag n.d. 3:87
Choir Invisible, The Hauser, Marianne McDowell, Obolensky n.d. 2:69
Chords and Dischords Franko, Sam Viking Press Inc. 1938 3:101
City and the Stars, The Clarke, Arthur C. Harcourt, Brace and Co. 1955 1:34
City of Trembling Leaves, The Clark, Walter van Tilburg Random House 1945 3:81
Cliffs of Fall Hazzard, Shirley Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:56
Clouded Moon, The Saltmarsh, Max Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Columbia Journal of World Business Columbia University Press 1965 1:14
Columbia Journal of World Business Columbia University Press n.d. 1:14
Come Unto These Yellow Sands Schenck, Earl Bobbs-Merrill n.d. 1:10
Complete Works of Lewis Carroll, The Carroll, Lewis Random House 1946 3:81
Conduct of Life, The Emerson, Ralph Waldo National House Library n.d. 2:73
Confessions of Felix Krull, Confidence man Mann, Thomas Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:55
Conspirators, The Prokosch, Frederic Harper 1942 1:35
Conspirators, The Prokosch, Frederic Harper 1942 1:36
Constitution Reconsidered, The Bainton, Roland, et al. Columbia University Press n.d. 1:13
Consultation Room Loomis, Frederic Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:52
Coronation Donoso, Jose Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:59
Corporation and the Arts, The Eells, Richard Columbia University Press n.d. 1:13
Court of Fair Maidens, The Speyer, Wilhelm Simon and Schuster Inc. 1936 3:93
Coward Heart, The Reiner, Anna Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:50
Crazy Doctor, The van der Lugt, Arie Random House 1954 3:82
Crazy Horse: The Strange Man of the Oglalas Sandoz, Mari Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:50
Crestwood Heights Loosley, E.W.; Seeley, John R. and Sim, R. Alexander Basic Books n.d. 1:8
Cross of Iron, The Heinrich, Williw Bobbs-Merrill n.d. 1:10
Crossing Point, The Charles, Gerda Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:56
D. H. Lawrence and Susan His Cow Tindall, William York Columbia University Press n.d. 1:13
Dark Rider Lara, Louis World Publ. Co. 1959 3:105
Dark Star, The Cost, March Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:52
Daughter of the House: A Reminiscence Ames, Evelyn Houghton Mifflin Co. 1961 1:42
Days of Our Years van Paassen, Pierre Hillman-Curl 1939 1:38
Days of Our Years van Paassen, Pierre Hillman-Curl 1939 1:39
Death in Venice Mann, Thomas Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:54
Death of the Heart, The Bowen, Elizabeth Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Decameron of Giovanni Boccaccio, The Winwar, Frances Random House 1955 3:82
Decline of the West, The Spencer, Oswald Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:53
Deep Valley Totheroh, Dan L.B. Fisher n.d. 1:24
Dem Wege zur amerikanischen Botschaft, Auf Seghers, Anna Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:44
Demian Hesse, Hermann Harper 1965 1:35
Demons, The von Doderer, Heimito Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:63
Depths and the Heights, The Romains, Jules Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Desk Standard Dictionary Funk & Wagnalls n.d. 1:29
Devil Is a Lonely Man, The Wood, Morrison Crowell Publishers n.d. 1:16
Devil That Failed, The Samuel, Maurice Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:55
Do Not Disturb Luling, Elizabeth Oxford University Press 1937 2:74
Doctor Faustus Mann, Thomas Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:55
Doctor for the People, A Shadid, Michael A. Vanguard 1939 3:100
Dream Merchants, The Robbins, Harold Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:55
Drums Along the Mohawk Edmonds, Walter D. Little Brown and Co. 1936 2:65
Duet in Discord Garner, Elizabeth Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Each Man's Son MacLennan, Hugh Little Brown and Co. 1950 2:66
Early Joys Fedin, Konstantin Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:59
East of Midnight Rosaire, Forrest Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:49
Education Before Verdun Zweig, Arnold Viking Press Inc. 1936 3:101
Ein Mann lernt fliegen Hauser, Heinrich S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:26
Ein Pfund Fleisser, Marielnise Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:45
Ein Sturmwind von Jamaika Hughes, Richard Erich Reiss Verlag n.d. 3:87
Einer gegen alle Graf, Oskar Maria Universitas, Berlin n.d. 3:99
Emotional Problems of Early Childhood Caplan, Gerland (ed.) Basic Books n.d. 1:8
England: die unbekannte Insel Cohen-Portheim, Paul Klinkhardt & Biermann Verlag n.d. 1:47
Englische Reise Priestley, J.B. S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:25
Episode of Sparrows, An Godden, Rumer Viking Press Inc. 1955 3:102
Erbe des Kapitans, Das Stock, hans Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:46
Erfolg Feuchtwnger, Lion Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:46
Escape of Socrates, The Pick, Robert Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:55
Europaische Diktaturen Sforza, Graf Carlo S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:25
Europaische Diktaturen Sforza, Graf Carlo S. Fisher Verlag, Berlin n.d. 1:27
Eva Chardonne, Jacques Erich Reiss Verlag n.d. 3:87
Evening of the Holiday, The Hazzard, Shirley Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:56
Every Man a Murderer von Doderer, Heimito Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:60
Exploration and Empire Goetzmann, William H. Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:59
Explorations in Social Psychiatry Clausen, John; Leighton, Alexander & Wilson, Robert Basic Books n.d. 1:8
Express to the East Doolard, A. Den Smith and Haas 1935 3:95
Fabulous People, The Hubner, Robert Norman Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:49
Fall of Paris, The Ehrenburg, Ilya Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:50
Familie Buchholz, Die Stinde, Julius G. Grote Verlag n.d. 1:32
Family Moskat, The Singer, Isaac Bashevis Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:49
Family's Affairs, A Douglas, Ellen Houghton Mifflin Co. 1961 1:42
Famous Science Fiction Stories Healy, Raymond and McComas, J. Francis (eds.) Random House 1945 3:81
Fang and Claw Buck, Frank Simon and Schuster Inc. 1934 3:93
Feindlichen Bruder, Die Sforza, Graf Carlo S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:27
Felding Castle de Born, Edith Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:60
Fifth Seal, The Aldanov, Mark Scribner and Co. 1943 3:92
Fight for Air Power, The Huie, William Bradford L.B. Fisher n.d. 1:24
Fine and Private Place, A Beagle, Peter S. Viking Press Inc. 1960 3:102
Firing Squad, The Weiskopf, F.C. Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:50
Five Families Lewis, Oscar Basic Books n.d. 1:8
Flagstad: A Personal Memoir McArthur, Edwin Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:57
Flea Circus Linn, Bettina Smith and Haas 1936 3:95
Flee The Angry Strangers Mandel, George Bobbs-Merrill n.d. 1:10
Foolish Wind, A Askham, Francis MacMillan 1947 2:70
Fortress in the Rice Appel, Benjamin Bobbs-Merrill n.d. 1:10
Four Stories Undset, Sigrid Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:57
Friedrich Paulsen, An Autobiography Paulsen, Friedrich Columbia University Press n.d. 1:13
Frontiers of Love, The Chang, Diana Random House 1956 3:82
Funger Weingart Shaw, George Bernard S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:27
Garden of the Finzi-Continis, The Bassani, Giorgio Atheneum n.d. 1:3
Gchmerzliches urfadien Mendelssohn, Peter Universitas, Berlin n.d. 3:99
Geese in the Forum Watkin, Lawrence Edward Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Gelmuna, der Sandmann, El Andre-Cuel, George Phonix-Verlag, Carl Siwinna n.d. 2:77
Generation Without Farewell Boyle, Kay Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:59
George F. Johnson and His Industrial Democracy Inglis, William Huntington Press n.d. 1:43
George F. Johnson and His Industrial Democracy Inglis, William Huntington Press n.d. 1:43
Geschichte der Philosophie Vorlander, Karl Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:45
Geschichte der Russischen Revolution Trotzki, Leo S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:25
Geschichte der Russischen Revolution Trotzki, Leo S. Fisher Verlag n.d. 1:27
Geschlecht und Charakter Weininger, Otto Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:46
Girls of Slender Means, The Spark, Muriel Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:58
Goblins of Eros, The Eyster, Warren Random House 1957 3:82
God's Frontier Descalzo, Jose Luis Martin Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:60
Golden Rose Hinkson, Pamela Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:51
Golden Wedding Pagano, Jo Random House 1942 2:80
Goldene Pfeil, Der Conrad, Joseph S. Fisher Verlag, Berlin n.d. 1:26
Good Man, A Young, Jefferson Bobbs-Merrill n.d. 1:10
Goodbye Japan Newman, Joseph L.B. Fisher n.d. 1:24
Granowsky Buhne Deutsch, Alexander Schmiede Verlag n.d. 3:91
Great Tales of Terror and the Supernatural Fraser, Phyllis and Wise, Herbert (eds.) Random House 1943 2:80
Green Laurels Peattie, Donald Culcross Simon and Schuster Inc. 1936 3:94
Griff in den Orient Matthias, Leo Bibliographisches Institut n.d. 1:9
Gustav Adolf Benninghoff, Ludwig Gebruder Enoch n.d. 1:31
Hamlet Shakespeare, William National House Library n.d. 2:73
Hans Brinker or the Silver Skates Dodge, Mary Mapes National House Library n.d. 2:73
Hard Blue Sky, the Grau, Shirley Ann Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:59
Hardy of Wessex Weber, Carl J. Columbia University Press n.d. 1:13
Hassliche Herzogin, Die Feuchtwanger, Lion Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:46
He Who Flees The Lion Klein-Haparash, J. Atheneum n.d. 1:3
Heathen Days Mencken, H.L. Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:49
Heaven Has No Favorites Remarque, Erich Maria Harcourt, Brace and Co. 1961 1:34
Henri und Sarah Levy, Sarah Erich Reiss Verlag n.d. 3:86
Here Was a Man Lofts, Norah Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:52
Heroic Love Loomis, Edward Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:53
Heroic Love Loomis, Edward Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:59
Herz der Finsternis, Das Conrad, Joseph S. Fisher Bucherei n.d. 1:26
Hiob: Der Roman eines einfachen Mannes Roth, Joseph Kiepenheuer n.d. 1:44
His Days Are As Grass Mergendahl, Charles Little Brown and Co. 1946 2:65
Holiday Greeting The Book-of-the-Month Club 1943 1:11
Holy Sinner, The Mann, Thomas Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:55
Home From the Sea Bermann, Richard A. Bobbs-Merrill n.d. 1:10
Hopscotch Cortazar, Julio Pantheon 1966 2:75
House in the Mulberry Tree, The Garrett, Zena Random House 1953 3:81
House in Vienna, The de Born, Edith Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:56
House on Coliseum Street, The Grau, Shirley Ann Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:58
Huguenots: Fighters for God and Human Freedom Zoff, Otto L.B. Fisher n.d. 1:24
I Met a Gypsy Lofts, Norah Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:53
Ich reise durch die Welt Pinner, Erna Erich Reiss Verlag n.d. 3:87
If I Have 4 Apples Frederich A. Stokes 1935 3:97
I'll Be Seeing You Barry, Henry Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:53
Image of Chekhov, The Payne, Robert Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:58
Impassioned Pygmies Winter, Keith Doubleday, Doran & Co. n.d. 1:18
In Another Language Thirlwall, John C. Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:61
In Defense of Love Gontard, Gert V. Alliance n.d. 1:2
In the Fine Summer Weather Whitcomb, Catharine Random House 1938 2:80
In the Sun Godden, Jon Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:53
In the Sun Godden, Jon Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:59
Inside Europe Gunther, John Harper 1939 1:37
Inside Europe Gunther, John The Book-of-the-Month Club 1943-46 1:11
Intermission in Europe Bartlett, Vernon Oxford University Press 1938 2:74
Into Thin Air Beck, Warren Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 2:55
Invaders, The Engstrand, Stuart David Knopf, Alfred A. n.d. 1:52
Iron Gates, The Millar, Margaret Random House 1945 3:81
Ivanhoe Scott, Sir Walter National House Library n.d. 2:73
Jeeney Ray Dornfield, Iris Viking Press Inc. 1962 3:102